"use strict";(self.webpackChunknatural_hazards_geoportal=self.webpackChunknatural_hazards_geoportal||[]).push([[622],{8622:function(e,t,n){n.r(t),n.d(t,{default:function(){return h}});var i=n(9439),o=n(2791),a=n(3433),s=n(184);var r=function(e){var t=e.ansClassNames,n=e.setAnsClassNames,i=e.correct,o=e.increaseScore,r=e.isAnswered,c=e.answers,u=e.showButton,l=function(e){if(!r){var s=e.currentTarget,c=Number(s.dataset.id),l=(0,a.Z)(t);c===i?(l[c-1]="right",o()):l[c-1]="wrong",n(l),u()}};return(0,s.jsx)("div",{id:"answers",children:(0,s.jsxs)("ul",{children:[(0,s.jsxs)("li",{onClick:l,className:t[0],"data-id":"1",children:[(0,s.jsx)("span",{children:"A"}),(0,s.jsx)("p",{children:c[0]})]}),(0,s.jsxs)("li",{onClick:l,className:t[1],"data-id":"2",children:[(0,s.jsx)("span",{children:"B"}),(0,s.jsx)("p",{children:c[1]})]}),(0,s.jsxs)("li",{onClick:l,className:t[2],"data-id":"3",children:[(0,s.jsx)("span",{children:"C"}),(0,s.jsx)("p",{children:c[2]})]}),(0,s.jsxs)("li",{onClick:l,className:t[3],"data-id":"4",children:[(0,s.jsx)("span",{children:"D"}),(0,s.jsx)("p",{children:c[3]})]})]})})},c=n(8818),u=function(e){var t=e.text,n=e.bck,i=e.color,o=e.link,a=e.target;return(0,s.jsx)(c.Z,{href:o,target:a,variant:"contained",size:"large",style:{background:n,color:i,margin:"20px",padding:"10px"},children:t})};var l=function(e){var t=e.style,n=e.score,a=e.total,r=e.startQuiz,c=e.count,l=e.MapName,d=(0,o.useState)({time:"start",title:"Welcome to Geospatial Smart Thinkers Quiz",text:"This is ".concat(l.Name," hazard quiz. <br /> There will be 15 questions. Only one of the options is correct."),buttonText:"Start the quiz"}),h=(0,i.Z)(d,2),p=h[0],g=h[1];(0,o.useEffect)((function(){c===a&&g({time:"end",title:"Congratulations!",buttonText:"Restart",text:"You have completed the quiz. <br /> You got: <strong>".concat(n,"</strong> out of <strong>").concat(a,"</strong> questions right.")})}),[c,a,n]);var f=p.title,m=p.text,w=p.buttonText;return(0,s.jsx)(s.Fragment,{children:(0,s.jsx)("div",{className:"popup-container",style:t,children:(0,s.jsx)("div",{className:"ml-5 col-md-10 col-10",children:(0,s.jsxs)("div",{className:"popup",children:[(0,s.jsx)("h1",{children:f}),(0,s.jsx)("p",{dangerouslySetInnerHTML:function(e){return{__html:e}}(m)}),(0,s.jsx)("span",{onClick:function(){"start"===p.time?r():window.location.reload(!1)},children:(0,s.jsx)(u,{text:w,bck:"#4d9584",color:"#fff"})})]})})})})},d=n(7689),h=function(){var e,t=(0,d.UO)();e="drought"===t.Name?n(7891).E9:"earthquake"===t.Name?n(7891).uN:"cyclone"===t.Name?n(7891).Zw:"flood"===t.Name?n(7891).pZ:"lighting"===t.Name?n(7891)._j:"epidemics"===t.Name?n(7891).o9:[];var a=(0,o.useState)(0),c=(0,i.Z)(a,2),u=c[0],h=c[1],p=(0,o.useState)(e.length),g=(0,i.Z)(p,1)[0],f=(0,o.useState)(!1),m=(0,i.Z)(f,2),w=m[0],y=m[1],v=(0,o.useState)(!1),A=(0,i.Z)(v,2),O=A[0],b=A[1],k=(0,o.useState)(0),Q=(0,i.Z)(k,2),W=Q[0],I=Q[1],T=(0,o.useState)("flex"),x=(0,i.Z)(T,2),S=x[0],C=x[1],q=(0,o.useState)(""),D=(0,i.Z)(q,2),N=D[0],j=D[1],M=(0,o.useState)([]),z=(0,i.Z)(M,2),P=z[0],E=z[1],L=(0,o.useState)(""),R=(0,i.Z)(L,2),H=R[0],Z=R[1],G=(0,o.useState)(["","","",""]),B=(0,i.Z)(G,2),F=B[0],_=B[1];(0,o.useEffect)((function(){U(u)}),[u]);var U=function(t){t>0&&t<=g&&(j(e[t-1].Question),E(e[t-1].Options),Z(e[t-1].Answer))};return(0,s.jsx)("div",{className:"main_page_container",children:(0,s.jsxs)("div",{className:"container",children:[(0,s.jsx)(l,{style:{display:S},MapName:t,score:W,total:g,startQuiz:function(){C("none"),h(1)},count:u}),(0,s.jsx)("div",{className:"question_page_heading",children:(0,s.jsx)("h1",{children:"Geospatial Smart Thinkers Quiz"})}),(0,s.jsx)("div",{className:"row",children:(0,s.jsxs)("div",{className:"col-lg-12 col-md-10",children:[(0,s.jsxs)("div",{id:"question",children:[(0,s.jsxs)("h4",{children:["Question ",u,"/",g]}),(0,s.jsx)("p",{children:N})]}),(0,s.jsx)(r,{answers:P,correct:H,showButton:function(){y(!0),b(!0)},isAnswered:O,increaseScore:function(){I(W+1)},ansClassNames:F,setAnsClassNames:_}),(0,s.jsx)("div",{id:"submit",children:w?(0,s.jsx)("button",{className:"fancy-btn",onClick:function(){u===g?C("flex"):(h(u+1),U(u),y(!1),b(!1),_(["","","",""]),b(!1))},children:u===g?"Finish quiz":"Next question"}):(0,s.jsx)("span",{})})]})})]})})}},7891:function(e,t,n){n.d(t,{E9:function(){return i},Zw:function(){return s},_j:function(){return r},o9:function(){return c},pZ:function(){return a},uN:function(){return o}});var i=[{Question:"What is drought?",Options:["A sudden flood event","An extended period of water abundance","A prolonged period of water scarcity","A volcanic eruption"],Answer:3},{Question:"Which of the following is a natural factor that can contribute to drought?",Options:["Efficient water management","High precipitation","Deforestation","Adequate rainfall"],Answer:3},{Question:"Which type of drought occurs when there is insufficient soil moisture to support crops?",Options:["Meteorological drought","Agricultural drought","Hydrological drought","Environmental drought"],Answer:2},{Question:"Which Indian state has a significant percentage of its population relying on agriculture for livelihood?",Options:["Maharashtra","Punjab","Kerala","Uttar Pradesh"],Answer:1},{Question:"The El Ni\xf1o phenomenon can influence drought occurrence by:",Options:["Increasing rainfall","Cooling ocean temperatures","Disrupting weather patterns","Reducing evaporation rates"],Answer:3},{Question:"What is the primary cause of drought?",Options:["Excessive rainfall","Overuse of water resources","Inadequate precipitation","Urbanization"],Answer:3},{Question:"What impact can drought have on the agriculture sector?",Options:["Increased crop yields","Reduced food prices","Crop failure and lower productivity","Improved livestock health"],Answer:3},{Question:"Which type of drought is characterized by water availability falling below levels that can be replenished by rainfall?",Options:["Meteorological drought","Agricultural drought","Hydrological drought","Environmental drought"],Answer:3},{Question:"Which region in India has a history of facing severe drought conditions?",Options:["Western Ghats","Himalayas","Gangetic Plain","Deccan Plateau"],Answer:4},{Question:"What environmental consequence can result from prolonged drought?",Options:["Increased water availability in lakes","Soil fertility improvement","Ecosystem imbalances and biodiversity loss","Enhanced aquatic habitat"],Answer:3},{Question:"What type of drought affects water-dependent infrastructure like hydropower plants and transportation systems?",Options:["Meteorological drought","Agricultural drought","Hydrological drought","Environmental drought"],Answer:3},{Question:"Which strategy aims to conserve water through practices like rainwater harvesting and water-efficient appliances?",Options:["Early Warning Systems","Water Use Regulation","Sustainable Land Management","Water Conservation"],Answer:4},{Question:"Which phenomenon is known for causing disruptions in global weather patterns and influencing drought occurrences?",Options:["El Ni\xf1o","Greenhouse effect","Desertification","Soil erosion"],Answer:1},{Question:"What is the primary economic impact of drought on agriculture?",Options:["Increased crop yields","Decreased income for farmers","Lower food prices","Reduced demand for agricultural products"],Answer:2},{Question:"Which administrative district is chronically affected by drought conditions in the state of Karnataka, India?",Options:["Bangalore","Tumkur","Belgaum","Mysore"],Answer:4}],o=[{Question:"What is an earthquake?",Options:["A sudden release of air pressure","A rapid movement of ocean currents","A sudden and violent shaking of the ground","A volcanic eruption"],Answer:3},{Question:"What causes most earthquakes?",Options:["Human activities","Meteorite impacts","Changes in atmospheric pressure","Movement of tectonic plates"],Answer:4},{Question:"The collision between which two tectonic plates has led to the formation of the Himalayas?",Options:["Indian Plate and Eurasian Plate","Pacific Plate and North American Plate","Eurasian Plate and African Plate","South American Plate and Antarctic Plate"],Answer:1},{Question:"Which region of India is particularly prone to seismic activity due to its position near tectonic plate boundaries?",Options:["Western Ghats","Indo-Gangetic plains","Deccan Plateau","Thar Desert"],Answer:2},{Question:"Which zone of India is categorized as having the highest seismic risk?",Options:["Zone of Very High Damage Risk","Zone of High Damage Risk","Zone of Moderate Damage Risk","Zone of Low Damage Risk"],Answer:1},{Question:"What is the purpose of earthquake hazard mitigation?",Options:["To predict the exact timing of earthquakes","To prevent earthquakes from occurring","To minimize the impact of earthquakes on society and the environment","To study the causes of earthquakes"],Answer:3},{Question:"What should you do during an earthquake if you are indoors and cannot find a sturdy piece of furniture to take cover under?",Options:["Stand by the window","Run outside immediately","Crouch near an inside wall","Stay where you are and jump"],Answer:3},{Question:"Which of the following is NOT a recommended action during an earthquake?",Options:["Stay indoors","Take cover under a sturdy piece of furniture","Cross your arms over your head and neck for protection","Turn off electrical connections if possible"],Answer:1},{Question:"What is the purpose of an early warning system for earthquakes?",Options:["To predict the exact magnitude of an earthquake","To provide information about earthquake causes","To give people time to take protective actions before strong shaking arrives","To prevent earthquakes from occurring"],Answer:3},{Question:"What type of earthquake mitigation measure involves strengthening existing buildings to meet modern seismic standards?",Options:["Land-use planning","Retrofitting","Infrastructure safeguarding","Green building practices"],Answer:2},{Question:"Which region of India is most vulnerable to powerful earthquakes due to the intensity of geological forces?",Options:["Western Ghats","Indo-Gangetic plains","Eastern coastal regions","Central plateaus"],Answer:2},{Question:"What is the primary cause of man-made earthquakes?",Options:["Volcanic activity","Human activities such as mining and construction","Changes in atmospheric pressure","Movement of tectonic plates"],Answer:2},{Question:"What is the recommended action if you're in a car during an earthquake?",Options:["Pull over to the side of the road and stay inside the car","Speed up and drive away from the epicenter","Abandon the car and run to an open area","Drive towards tall buildings for protection"],Answer:1},{Question:"Why does India experience earthquakes?",Options:["Due to excessive rainfall","Due to volcanic activity","Due to movement of tectonic plates","Due to high wind speeds"],Answer:3},{Question:"What is the primary goal of earthquake hazard mitigation?",Options:["To prevent all earthquakes from occurring","To predict the exact timing of earthquakes","To minimize the impact of earthquakes on society and the environment","To create artificial earthquakes for research purposes"],Answer:3}],a=[{Question:"What is a flood?",Options:["A sudden gust of wind","A high tide on the coast","An overflow of water onto normally dry land","A drought in a region"],Answer:3},{Question:"Which of the following is NOT a factor that can cause floods?",Options:["Strong winds","Heavy rainfall","Snow accumulation","Dam failure"],Answer:1},{Question:"Coastal floods are primarily caused by:",Options:["Rapid snowmelt","Storm surges and storm tides","Excessive groundwater","Urbanization"],Answer:2},{Question:"Flash floods occur due to:",Options:["Intense rainfall within a short period","Gradual snowmelt","Long-lasting rainfall","High tides"],Answer:1},{Question:"Fluvial floods occur when:",Options:["Coastal areas experience storm surges","Rivers overflow their banks","Groundwater levels rise suddenly","Snow accumulates rapidly"],Answer:2},{Question:"Which type of flood is caused by the failure of moraine dams containing a glacial lake?",Options:["Coastal flood","Flash flood","Pluvial flood","Glacial Lake Outburst Flood (GLOF)"],Answer:4},{Question:"What is the primary purpose of floodplain zoning?",Options:["Encouraging urbanization in flood-prone areas","Preventing construction in flood-prone areas","Promoting agricultural activities in floodplains","Enhancing water flow during floods"],Answer:2},{Question:"What role does flood forecasting play in flood mitigation?",Options:["It prevents floods from occurring","It helps in timely evacuation and preparedness.","It creates floods intentionally.","It decreases the intensity of floods."],Answer:2},{Question:"Which of the following is a flood mitigation measure related to infrastructure?",Options:["Encouraging deforestation","Constructing embankments along rivers","Increasing impervious surfaces in urban areas","Diverting river flow for irrigation"],Answer:2},{Question:"What is the purpose of elevating critical infrastructure like roads and bridges?",Options:["To prevent earthquakes","To increase traffic flow","To enhance flood resistance","To decrease construction costs"],Answer:3},{Question:"What is the key benefit of afforestation in flood mitigation?",Options:["It prevents all floods from occurring.","It decreases soil erosion and runoff.","It increases the speed of water flow.","It reduces the need for early warnings."],Answer:2},{Question:"What does a flood-resistant building design involve?",Options:["Constructing buildings with no windows","Building structures entirely underground","Designing buildings that can withstand flooding","Constructing buildings with no foundations"],Answer:3},{Question:"How can remote sensing and GIS contribute to flood management?",Options:["By monitoring and mapping flood-prone areas","By causing floods intentionally","By predicting earthquake occurrences","By creating artificial embankments"],Answer:1},{Question:"Which of the following is NOT a flood mitigation measure?",Options:["Riverbank stabilization","Early warning systems","Encouraging construction in flood-prone areas","Flood forecasting"],Answer:3},{Question:"How does climate change impact flood mitigation strategies?",Options:["It reduces the need for mitigation measures.","It decreases the severity of floods.","It eliminates the occurrence of floods.","It can lead to increased flood risks."],Answer:4}],s=[{Question:"What are the three stages of cyclones, based on their intensity?",Options:["Mild, Moderate, Severe","Tropical, Severe, Super","Early, Developing, Intense","Low, Medium, High"],Answer:2},{Question:"What is the minimum wind speed for a tropical cyclone?",Options:["50 miles per hour","74 miles per hour","100 miles per hour","120 miles per hour"],Answer:2},{Question:"Which term is commonly used for a tropical cyclone in the North Atlantic and Northeast Pacific?",Options:["Cyclone","Typhoon","Hurricane","Tornado"],Answer:3},{Question:"At what wind speed does a tropical cyclone become a severe cyclone?",Options:["50-75 mph","76-100 mph","101-120 mph","121-150 mph"],Answer:3},{Question:"What factor triggers the formation of cyclones?",Options:["High atmospheric pressure","Cold sea surface temperatures","Low atmospheric pressure over warm water","Dense cloud cover"],Answer:3},{Question:"What is the role of atmospheric pressure in cyclone formation?",Options:["It has no effect on cyclones","It causes cyclones to dissipate","Low pressure over warm water ","High pressure over warm water "],Answer:3},{Question:"Which of the following is NOT a potential effect of cyclones on India?",Options:["Heavy rainfall","Severe drought","Strong winds","Storm surges"],Answer:2},{Question:"What is the purpose of storm surge models?",Options:["To predict rainfall during cyclones","To monitor seismic activity","To estimate the intensity of cyclones","To predict potential coastal flooding during cyclones"],Answer:4},{Question:"What should you do with outdoor items during a cyclone?",Options:["Secure or bring them indoors","Leave them as they are","Scatter them around to reduce impact","Tie them to trees"],Answer:1},{Question:"What is the primary agency responsible for cyclone monitoring and prediction in India?",Options:["National Disaster Management Authority (NDMA)","Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO)","Indian Meteorological Department (IMD)","Central Water Commission (CWC)"],Answer:3},{Question:"What should you do if you're in a coastal area during a cyclone?",Options:["Stay on the beach to watch the waves","Go swimming in the sea","Avoid coastal areas and move to safer locations","Take photographs of the storm surge"],Answer:3},{Question:"What should you avoid using during a power outage caused by a cyclone?",Options:["Flashlights","Candles","Battery-powered radios","Generators"],Answer:2},{Question:"What should you do if local authorities announce an evacuation during a cyclone?",Options:["Ignore the announcement and stay at home","Follow the evacuation plan and move to designated safe areas","Immediately go to the nearest beach","Call friends for a gathering"],Answer:2},{Question:"What is the purpose of aircraft reconnaissance during cyclones?",Options:["To observe cloud formations","To study ocean currents","To create visuals for news reports","To collect real-time data about the cyclone's structure and intensity"],Answer:4},{Question:"What is the main goal of cyclone preparedness efforts?",Options:["To predict the exact path of cyclones","To minimize the impact of cyclones on communities and infrastructure","To create stronger cyclones for research purposes","To increase wind speed during cyclones"],Answer:2}],r=[{Question:"What is lightning?",Options:["A type of rain","A sudden earthquake","A natural electrical discharge during thunderstorms","A form of hail"],Answer:3},{Question:"Lightning is caused by the movement of:",Options:["Water droplets in the atmosphere","Electrical charges within clouds and between clouds and the ground","Air currents within clouds","Sound waves during thunderstorms"],Answer:2},{Question:"Which type of lightning is the most common?",Options:["Cloud-to-Cloud Lightning","Intra-Cloud Lightning","Cloud-to-Ground Lightning","Sheet Lightning"],Answer:1},{Question:"What is the primary reason for the increase in lightning activity during thunderstorms?",Options:["Intense rain","Wind patterns","Separation of positive and negative charges within clouds","The presence of large hailstones"],Answer:3},{Question:"Which season in India is associated with a higher frequency of lightning strikes?",Options:["Winter","Spring","Summer","Monsoon"],Answer:4},{Question:"Which organization developed the Damini lightning alert app?",Options:["Indian Institute of Technology (IIT)","Indian Institute of Tropical Meteorology (IITM)","Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO)","Indian Meteorological Department (IMD)"],Answer:2},{Question:"What is the purpose of the Damini app?",Options:["Provide real-time weather forecasts","Alert users about thunderstorms","Track earthquakes","Monitor air pollution levels"],Answer:2},{Question:"What does the term 'intra-cloud lightning' refer to?",Options:["Lightning between two distant clouds","Lightning between a cloud and the ground","Lightning within a single thunderstorm cloud","Lightning that forms inside a building"],Answer:3},{Question:"What safety precautions should people take during thunderstorms to avoid lightning strikes?",Options:["Use electronic devices outdoors","Seek shelter indoors or in a car","Stand under tall trees","Swim in a lake or pool"],Answer:2},{Question:"Which Indian states report the highest number of lightning strike deaths?",Options:["Kerala and Maharashtra","Punjab and Rajasthan","Bihar, Jharkhand, Uttar Pradesh, and West Bengal","Tamil Nadu and Andhra Pradesh"],Answer:3},{Question:"What is the average number of lightning-related deaths in India per year, according to the National Crime Records Bureau?",Options:["500","2,300","1,000","5,000"],Answer:2},{Question:"What does the lightning location network established by the IITM aim to achieve?",Options:["Track the migration patterns of birds","Monitor pollution levels in cities","Detect and locate lightning strikes with high accuracy","Predict earthquakes"],Answer:3},{Question:"What is the purpose of the lightning map mentioned in the data?",Options:["Display current weather conditions","Show areas prone to earthquakes","Indicate regions with heavy rainfall","Illustrate lightning strike data in different time frames"],Answer:4},{Question:"Which type of lightning has the potential to cause significant damage to property?",Options:["Cloud-to-Cloud Lightning","Intra-Cloud Lightning","Sheet Lightning","Cloud-to-Ground Lightning"],Answer:4},{Question:"Lightning strikes can lead to psychological trauma such as:",Options:["Fear of rain","Post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD)","Aversion to thunderstorms","Claustrophobia"],Answer:2}],c=[{Question:"What is the term used to describe the abrupt outbreak of a disease within a particular community during a specific period?",Options:["Pandemic","Outbreak","Epidemic","Endemic"],Answer:3},{Question:"The name 'corona' for the coronavirus is inspired by:",Options:["Its circular shape","The virus's genetic code","The crown-like spikes on its surface","Its high mutation rate"],Answer:3},{Question:"Which of the following diseases is NOT caused by a coronavirus?",Options:["COVID-19","MERS","SARS","Malaria"],Answer:4},{Question:"Which term refers to an infectious disease that spreads across countries or continents?",Options:["Epidemic","Outbreak","Pandemic","Endemic"],Answer:3},{Question:"Which mosquito-borne disease remains a major health concern in parts of India, particularly in warm and humid climates?",Options:["Influenza","Dengue","Tuberculosis","Diabetes"],Answer:2},{Question:"What are the crown-like spikes on the surface of the coronavirus responsible for?",Options:["Replicating the virus","Attaching to host cells","Causing fever symptoms","Inducing coughing"],Answer:2},{Question:"Which disease is characterized by high fever, severe joint and muscle pain, and sometimes bleeding?",Options:["Dengue","Malaria","Tuberculosis","Anemia"],Answer:1},{Question:"Anemia is characterized by a deficiency of which component in the blood?",Options:["White blood cells","Plasma","Platelets","Red blood cells"],Answer:4},{Question:"What is the primary mode of transmission for COVID-19?",Options:["Direct skin contact","Airborne droplets","Contaminated food","Swimming in infected water"],Answer:2},{Question:"What is the purpose of wearing a mask to prevent COVID-19?",Options:["To keep the face warm","To protect the eyes","To prevent sneezing","To reduce the spread of respiratory droplets"],Answer:4},{Question:"What organization declared COVID-19 as a global pandemic?",Options:["UNICEF","WHO","CDC","Red Cross"],Answer:2},{Question:"Which of the following diseases is NOT caused by a virus?",Options:["Malaria","Dengue","COVID-19","SARS"],Answer:1},{Question:"What is the primary reason for the spread of malaria in India?",Options:["Poor air quality","Contaminated water","Mosquito bites","Foodborne transmission"],Answer:3},{Question:"Which of the following diseases is characterized by a deficiency of iron, vitamin B12, or folic acid?",Options:["Anaemia","Diabetes","Tuberculosis","Dengue"],Answer:1},{Question:"What is the recommended approach to address iron deficiency anemia?",Options:["Promoting regular exercise","Providing vitamin D supplementation","Increasing mosquito control measures","Fortifying staple foods with iron"],Answer:4}]}}]);
//# sourceMappingURL=622.3f1506de.chunk.js.map